About

A young and hardworking, Chartered Accountant with proficiency in a diverse set of indirect taxation Advisory, Consultancy, Litigation and Compliances

With a good understanding of GST, Custom, DGFT, FTP related queries, and a keen interest in indirect taxation, now actively seeking an opportunity to work with a reputed organization and build a promising career in the field of Indirect Taxation.

Mohd Khalid

Chartered Accountant

DOB – 05.10.1990 Experience – 4years

Location - Delhi / NCR

P: +91-8586958613

E: camohd.khalid0510@gmail.com

Professional Skills

- Comprehensive understanding of GST, Central Excise, Service Tax & Customs
- Drafting & Filing of replies to show cause notices and appeals before adjudicating & appellate authorities of GST,
 Customs, Central Excise & Service tax departments.
- Drafting and filing of replies to Scrutiny Assessment and filing of Appeal before CIT(A)
- Drafting & filing of applications and submissions before settlement commission, special valuation branch, refund department and DGFT regarding advance licences & EPCG licences.
- Hands-on experience of representation before CIT(A), settlement Commission, CESTAT, PMLA tribunal, FEMA tribunal & assisted in filing of writ petition before the Hon'ble High Court in eCODS scheme.
- Advisory & consultation on GST, foreign trade policy, Customs, Central Excise & Service Tax.
- Incorporation of Company and LLP

Work Experience

Indirect Tax Practitioner with M/s VKF and Associates LLP (January 2019 to present)
Indirect Tax Practitioner with M/s Piyush Kumar and Associates (May 2016 to December 2018)

- Representation before Commissioner and Additional Commissioner of GST, Central Excise and Service Tax, Custom, CESTAT, and Settlement Commission Bench, Enforcement Directorate under PMLA, PMLA tribunal and FEMA Tribunal.
- Drafting, filing & Submissions
 - o Response to Show Cause Notice before the GST Authorities, GST Appeals before Commissioner and Additional Commissioner of GST, and filing of GSTR- 3B, GSTR- 1, GSTR-9, GSTR-9C and GST Registration
 - Settlement Commission Application, Response to Show Cause Notices before adjudicating authorities of Central Excise and Service Tax; Central Excise and Service Tax Appeals before Commissioner and CESTAT, Application for Consequential refund, Income-tax Appeals before the CIT(A), Reply to Show Cause Notices before the Enforcement Directorate under PMLA and FEMA, submissions in respect of Advance License and EPCG License under DGFT

Internship

M/s Gulati and Malik – Inter and Paid Assistan (September 2008 to March 2015)

- Assisted in Tax Audit and filing of tax Audit report, Bank Audit, registration under DVAT, Central Excise and Service Tax, preparation of CARO, incorporation of new company, LLP firms and filing of various forms with MCA, providing tax opinions to clients & Finalization of Balance Sheets.
- Preparation & filing of DVAT, Service tax and Central Excise returns, TDS returns and issuance of forms 16 and 16A,
 submissions in response to Income-tax notices. Finalization of Income tax return of Individuals, Firms and Company and advisory on Direct and Indirect Taxation Compliances

Educational Qualifications

November 2015	Chartered Accountancy-Final	53.38%	ICAI, New Delhi
December 2018	M.com	54.78%	IGNOU, New Delhi
March 2008	RPVV, Civil Lines	70.40	CBSE, New Delhi
March 2006	GBSSS, Pratap Bagh	67.60	CBSE, New Delhi